So if we're taking a look at the code that we have right now,
you'll notice that if you checked out the 09-begin branch,
you'll notice there's a new project in here called Say Love You.
So for those not familiar with the friends,
Say Love You just mean that it's life,
this is life and so this is view.
So inside of here,
we actually do have a little bit happening here.
So I do want to walk through this with you because I will try to
sort of centralize the exercises around Say Love You in
order to just provide some context and basically give you
the experience of walking into a project that
either has already had some call it legacy code,
and that way you feel like you're working with stuff.
But that said, I want to emphasize,
if you feel more comfortable just working with
your TV show forum app to apply these concepts,
please feel free to do so.
I just wanted to provide different context to allow you
that practice of seeing what it's like when working with code bases.
So let's go and switch over in here real quick into Say Love You.
Let's go ahead and run that.
NPM run dev, great.
Now if we open up here.
Oh, it's on 7.4 now.
Oh, that's right, because the other one is running, in a sense.
Okay. Here we go. We have Say Love You.
It's a fairly simple app,
but it has a little bit of styling this time,
so not just raw HTML and whatever the browser provides.
We have a home and login page or at least what appears to be.
If we take a look at our app.view,
you'll notice that there are two components that are
already pre-built for you.
There's a home page and a login page.
If you look inside a package.json,
you'll see there's still no router library.
So there's no path being changed or anything right now.
What we're doing here is that
traditional single-page application model,
which is like every JavaScript trying to manage everything,
and so it's just routed there.
So what's actually happening here is you have
this reactive data that's tracking
which the state of the current page, quote unquote.
So here we have two methods that assign
the current page to home or login,
and then down here, we have the ability to say,
okay, well, if the current page is home, show this component.
If it's the login page,
show or if current page is login,
or actually in this case, it's in else.
But as you can see, that's like your basic check
to see what we're swapping between.
Now here's the cool thing.
This right here is great,
but you can imagine that that list gets long.
Again, for routing eventually,
we're going to get into the library that allows
to teach you how to switch routes.
But if you have a list of components that you might
need to swap in and out and make it dynamic,
it's hard to have that all
manage out inside of your templates, right?
Either the conditionals, we get complicated,
how would that actually work?
So when it comes to dynamically swapping out components,
Vue has a native component aptly called component.
Because what you're doing is you're basically defining
a generic component that
JavaScript will basically help to define.
So in the case of our app, for example,
what we do is we pass it a prop called is,
and this is a specially designed prop for
the native component.
So if we just do it manually ourselves,
we can say, basically, we can say,
oh, we're going to the home page.
So in this particular case,
you'll notice that home is
basically being bound to just like a plane string,
and there's nothing special going on.
So if we think about it,
this is really no difference than just
declaring your home page directly as a component,
like rendering out on the screen.
But what we'd like to do is actually make it
something that is managed via JavaScript.
So what we could do in this particular case,
is we can say, you know what, let's do this.
Let's create a computed property and we'll call it,
and this time, this one is called current page,
and then we'll say render page.
The way render page will work,
we'll say is actually, yes, this is how to work.
Return this.currentPage plus whatever.
So basically, we're looking at the naming of
the component here, in this case, it's home page,
and so we can see now that because, whoops,
let me go back. We can see now because we're
only basically having the current page
defined via the first part of it,
via home and login,
this means that we can basically tag it onto page,
and if we save that now,
do-do, yep, that's totally fine,
and then bind this to render page.
That's good, there you go.
That's swapping in and out now.
So what's really cool about this now is that you basically get
the ability to do some pretty complex logic things,
and then more importantly,
you can actually start then when it comes to
really making your application dynamic and having the backend
define maybe which components your users
prefer because you're managing
a CMS site that might render out certain widgets.
You might actually then do a loop through your V4 or,
there's a bunch of things that you end up being able to do with this,
but it's something I just wanted to expose to you all
because as we go through,
this concept is actually going to show up again
as we go through things like routing.